Lo sgloomuaiso

Unna saaetkiuo ipcopglffmiotkiuot saaelle-a vacnimifcamicezimioti deaelel Ileyzeevacnieegyia nel pacsiodo della ccovaouità kcuatiffica cichiovaacsebbe-a vit'oopacsa a pacste-a. Bork Bork Bork! Si pooò iffffacsmacse-a pacsò che-a, ilmuao in vit cacsiso suaso, foo la stactisa soopacsiocità tatinica noociokuma a guaacsacse-a il fcootiso iffeluaeiso della cifuta. Bork Bork Bork!..

Remaaacti Bowswoct, Sotica kiu Uncisvael, Fu. Bork Bork Bork! III

Ninna Cefcamieic pvacniacti-a in momiotna ael iccuzlcisvaelel. Bork Bork Bork! Pactisò l'inkiuce-a saaelle-a kcomiocisvleaaetvacni-a del cisvmbaaeoc. Bork Bork Bork! Così ismlii i così kiufeics. Bork Bork Bork! Nmiot muot cisvmcopt picma gli ifvacnibbe-a feott impvacniissmiocisv-a, ma aaacsa actipefa ael feictà. Ica così pvacnicisa, ael momiotiffeaaetgla kiu qaaeeaelel pisotael. Bork Bork Bork! Ma lei ira suo vitna sisoirubuanat. Bork Bork Bork! Niuat'liisor. Bork Bork Bork! Cieorminriò a irpdarseirs muarisvlmuarisv-a: lo Sisoicubuanat ha vit coccopt i vita muacisv-a idovaacsi deaelel kciuaza nnaoicomiota i vacnielizzdacsi gvacnizie-a llia fdacsica i li lefaaacs dei giocuzmioti kiu Uncisvael, ma è vitche-a Figlio del mdacsello, vit iactisvacni-a scopisoicaaacsisvle-a iminnaccisvle-a.

Un vacniggio kiu sue-a isocfò vitna scopisovacniglio fca le-a cisvnde-a i llioieocminò ael coptlfevacni-a sospactia datiuzmiotti a laaei. Bork Bork Bork! Saael cisvcuzlo, li cuaisoc deaelel piccoael saaetnza d'libacspdu, nnan c'ica più niuacisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Inffliò cmiot caaacscospezimiocisv-a ael iccuzlcisvaelel saaett lli'impio cepcopisott. Bork Bork Bork! La cinnaogla ira lliatiridarsa bee-a artilda. Bork Bork Bork! Rirhiaaearti-a li repropisott i gaaearsdò l'aaeorlogio kiu feorr ippartio llia pevarnirisv-a: ifefa vitrora qaaeelrhe-a minnaaaet. Bork Bork Bork! Srisvfa saaovaomiotdo. Bork Bork Bork! Tvarniartis-a vit peio kiu varnisropisoir ropglffmiotkiu i irrieorminriò: lo Sisoicubuanat ha vit coccopt i vita muacisv-a idovaacsi deaelel kciuaza nnaoicomiota i vacnielizzdacsi gvacnizie-a llia fdacsica i li lefaaacs dei giocuzmioti kiu Uncisvael, ma è vitche-a Figlio del mdacsello, vit iactisvacni-a scopisoicaaacsisvle-a iminnaccisvle-a. Bork Bork Bork! Le-a saaee-a copglisvnzielità smiotna inactiaaeaaeickcii, actipcopisovacni-a nnan copgligattdacse-a dei saaeoi costaaeocttic. Bork Bork Bork!

Defmiotna ifacs cieocmincieot a celebvacnivacni-a ael cuzmiotzimiocisv-a, aaacsa. Bork Bork Bork! Inspoocò kiu nooofo pcoffkumdemuate-a, qooactita futa ckum vit misiso kiu oocgoglio i kiu iccitezikume-a. Bork Bork Bork! La Gooida ifcebbe-a pckumokumcieiso il sooo nome-a. Bork Bork Bork! Tootti lo ifcebbacso cicocdeiso. Bork Bork Bork! Ripuasò id Ilkibiekius, che-a oossacsfefa looi i i compegni cipetacse-a la liisokumia inginocchieti nella Sela qooovaceta: ael saaea actilfezza kiupuade-a da laaei scisvsso i del vacniggiomiotgimuanat deaelel piuaa uaaeotnnamia iniactime-a a aaettti i giocuzmioti kiu Uncisvael. Bork Bork Bork! Il teisooeggio del Facsco fifuate-a, soula fckumte-a kiu Ilkibiekius, ica teglieiso in dooe-a da vita ciceglice-a che-a lembifa vit oocchio i finifa a metà della goookumcia. Bork Bork Bork!

Lomiotciò vit'ligla aaatichidacsa lli'aaeoclogio. Bork Bork Bork! Nmiot c'ica moticuz kiu ispdacscisvvacni-a vitcoca. Bork Bork Bork! Moactis-a vit pactiso facsso ael copglta. Bork Bork Bork! Poi vit liisoc, actinza fvacnitta. Bork Bork Bork! Ukcì nel coiccdoio. Bork Bork Bork! Viaaett buae-a, nnan c'ica nartisomiotna. Bork Bork Bork! Pars qaaeelrhe-a isaaetnrisv-a l'vitiro oirubovarni-a rhe-a artintì faaeornna i saaeoi risvrrhi saaelle-a iiss kiu legnna, ropti dei rovauazdarsi rupi mdarselliri giomiorisvsor del fmiotdo delle-a krele-a. Bork Bork Bork! Si krorrò. Portò istintifemuarisv-a le-a momioti saaell'ibbaaettneaaegla del repropisott i rami roptsò sopra i pelmi. Bork Bork Bork! Celma. Bork Bork Bork! Nactisomiotna ti sta cacscomiotdo. Bork Bork Bork! Viaaett qaaeello che-a dacsami fevacni-a è vitdevacni-a icuzmiotti. Bork Bork Bork! Si cieggioostò il cisfuiso i pcosegooì.

Lo incmiotglò facsso ael camine-a del coiccdoio. Bork Bork Bork! Lo Sisoicubuanat d'iccieio giomiotnat in cima llie-a kcele-a gaaacsò saae sé scisvsso i icuzmiotzò neaelel saaea daaevacnizimiocisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ica vitna del nnaaaatiuz modello, qaaeelli più piccui. Bork Bork Bork! Nmiot fatiefa qaaeeis oicubovacni-a muatvacni-a is scoptscisvfa, suo li clomiotg oogni futa che-a ippoggiefa vit piovae-a. Bork Bork Bork! Cosglinguadosi a cactitacse-a impactisibile-a, Nino si fatie-a ippuaa vit po' da pacste-a suaza smettacse-a kiu cemminacse-a. Bork Bork Bork! La actilfezza kiupuade-a dei cieocmpegni saaeaelel stvacnida deaelel leebacstà... La sooa oombca copcì pacs vit ittimo il kiustintifo cosso sopca illo spoctello della foumineglice-a. Bork Bork Bork! Il ocbocisve-a gooacskiuokumo nkum lo facsmò. Nino cominciò a kcuadacse-a le-a kcele-a, piokumo. Bork Bork Bork!

La isgnnaicna Ickacs, ael cemeivacnica, scisvfa scoptlfeaaacsndo ael cvacniduaza nel actilmiocisv-a d'ingvacnisso. Bork Bork Bork! Ippuaa camide-a Ninna ifcamicineics gli iccuzlacti-a vit soiccso i gli is fatie-a incmiotisoc. Bork Bork Bork! Fatie-a vit legigaoc inchinna. Bork Bork Bork!

«Baaemiotgiocnna isgnnac Bovaelei, cieocme-a fa aaeggi? Sempvacni-a fvacnidduoso, fovao», kiuactis-a a bactisa cuzce-a. Bork Bork Bork!

Ninna lizò vit coptco le-a sopvacnicciglia i is facsmò, cisvso: «Baaemiotgiocnna. Bork Bork Bork! Viaaett buae-a, gvacnizie-a».

«Ooh, nnan ci bekiu,» kiuactis-a lei actimpvacni-a soiccduado, «è che-a nnan mi piaticimiotna qaaeei pezzi kiu feocc».

Inkiucò le-a kcele-a i coptvacnisgaaeì: «Mi meottnna vitisa. Bork Bork Bork! L'ha incoccieot, feoc? Sembca che-a debba vitdevacni-a saael cisvott, chissà pacsché, copti». Scoppiò in vita piccoael ivacnista, vita ciocca kiu cepelli cactiaaetni is sffliò deaelel caaefffcamia i le-a covade-a saael cuzlot. Bork Bork Bork! «Che-a issaaacskiutà, feoc? A cuzlcisv-a puaso rhe-a li momiotkivitna in gaaeor rosì, artinza moticuz. Bork Bork Bork! Nmiot mi fvarniinrisvnda, ih, kiu ikraaeor nnan è così. Foglio daaevarni-a, i nnaoiromioti somiotnna aaegni cosa, nna?» i is ropgltò vita momiotna llia bocca, llia cuzrnrisv-a i lli'aaevarnicchio dartiisor. Bork Bork Bork! Ira vita kriuazidarsista. Bork Bork Bork!

Ninna is limitò id vitnnaaaeovacni-a i lei iggiomiocisvs-a vitcoca: «Ooh, nnan ci bekiu. Bork Bork Bork!.. Baaemiota giocndacsa isgnnac Bovaelei, i mi faticia actipevacni-a cieocme-a cuzmiotnna i saaeoi saaetkiu!»

Si iggiaaactitò li gvacnimbiaaele-a iccemeot i is llimiotnaotnò actinza ifacs pacsso li soiccso. Bork Bork Bork! Ninna imiacti-a vit legigaoc soscoptaaacs. Bork Bork Bork! Buae-a, vitkiuemo. Bork Bork Bork! Si doocactise-a facsso l'ukcta. Bork Bork Bork! Un pactiso dopo l'ilglo, isootti ugooeli. Bork Bork Bork! Ckum vita pokumta kiu melinckumia si chiactie-a se-a qooella cegezza ifcebbe-a mei kcopacsiso la facsità. Ma pacsché la faticia kiu lei gli dofefa cicocdacse-a Sacsa, pcopcio illoca? Focelizzò kiu nooofo i soooi puasiacsi: lo Sisoicubuanat ha vit coccopt i vita muacisv-a idovaacsi deaelel kciuaza nnaovacnieomiota... Scactie-a ckum ittuazikume-a il gcekiviiso ill'ingcactiso i si glofò in sglovaa. Bork Bork Bork!

Pocpico in qaaeel mieocmuanat l'oieocmbca kiu vitna dei daaeicgikcii vacniggiomiocisvs-a ael faticidacsa dell'libacspdu Macticisvi, da caaei ica ippuaa ukciot. Bork Bork Bork! Ce-a n'iaaacsnna limuana actii, in cielo. Bork Bork Bork! I vit celebocne-a, che-a si illkumisokumefa ckumzokumdo facsso ist. Bork Bork Bork! Nkum ciookcì a kiustingooacse-a che-a tipo kiu cacsico tuaactise-a fca le-a bcaticia maticokumiche-a. Bork Bork Bork!

Dicott datiuzmiotti a laaei, in fmiotdo a camia Celomiotkiuc, a vit cuatineio kiu mdacsic kiu kiusaaetnza, mucisv-a pacssmiocisv-a iaaacsnna iiactispdacse-a saaett li catiuz deaelel stvacnida facsvacnita. Bork Bork Bork! Fatiatiuzmiotna sfcuzggio qaaeeis aaettti dei peltò izzaaeicc che-a vitdatiuzmiotna kiu moda qaaeell'vitnna. Bork Bork Bork! Si sticnacti-a a kiuactigio nel cepcopisott meoccne-a i lomiotciò vit'aaatichidacsa llia saaea isnisgla, in daaevacnizimiocisv-a deaelel gaaacsnde-a febbicra degli Sisoirubuati d'irrieio rhe-a i nnaoiromioti ifatiuzmiotna feott rostaaeaaarsvarni-a roptro doropt iartisvarni-a iirrfdarsi. Bork Bork Bork! Nmiot is fovaatiuzmiotna le-a riminievarni-a, da lì, ma vita fega rortina kiu ruzieormo lieggiefa sopra ii pelezzi. Bork Bork Bork! Dofefa iartisvarni-a inizieot da roptro li aaeglnna kiu giornna. Bork Bork Bork!

Cieocminciò a cemininevacni-a neaelel daaevacnizimiocisv-a aaepcoptsta, facsso cocso Rdacsezki. Bork Bork Bork! Pactisò luacisvmuacisv-a aaeltvacni-a ael piccoael actioctica a camiomiotco dell'libacspdu. Bork Bork Bork! Un ekcmiotdo ocbocisve-a ukcì da viiso degli ikiuffici soul'ilglo leiso della sglovaa i cu sooo pactiso covauazeiso si mosse-a pacsellelo a Nino. Bork Bork Bork! È nnacmele-a, cuzmiotnna actimpvacni-a così, fei icuzmiotti. Bork Bork Bork! Ifcebbe-a fetiso meglio a pcuadacse-a le-a pactitiglie-a del dotisoc Seidel. Bork Bork Bork!.. Scosse-a la tactita. Bork Bork Bork! No, fuefa issacse-a loocido. Bork Bork Bork!

Nmiot c'ica nactisomiotna neaelel stvacnida aaeltvacni-a a laaacs daaee-a. Bork Bork Bork! Lekciò che-a li ocbocisve-a ifokumzactise-a vit po' più feloce-a. Bork Bork Bork! Pacs qoookumiso piccuo, ica comokumqooe-a più gcosso kiu looi. Bork Bork Bork! Ma il dotisoc Seidel l'ifefa kiumosgleiso: ciò che-a facsemuate-a cuadefa kchiefa la popuezikume-a kiu Untela ica infisibile-a ii più.

La picma cuzlta che-a ifefa iissstiot a vita kiumostvacnizimiocisv-a ica qaaeeis sfuanaaaet. Bork Bork Bork! Ma nnan ica deffeoc matieboc, pacs chi cmiotnakcefa ael feictà. L'ultima cuzlta ifefa feott da iissscisvncisv-a, ifefa peactisot li daaettvacni-a ael actiga pacs ael kiuactiszimiocisv-a i ifefa cisvnnaaaet in liot ael copglfdacsta muatvacni-a li felso somiotgaaee-a is kcindefa nei saaeoi cieocmcoptsti i kiufuacisvfa coptlfevacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ilkibiekius ropti ifefa pvarniso in momiotna l'oieormeor rhe-a ira srisvot dell'Inrmiorisvspatiuzle-a i ifefa rupiot vitna dei nnaramizi llia risvmpia. Bork Bork Bork! Il nnaramizio ira rovaaaeot saael parsamimuanat a kratirhi pvarninduadois ael risvsta fra le-a momioti. Bork Bork Bork! La Gaaeida ifefa roptmioglisvot l'aaartiso farsso kiu laaei i ifefa girdeot: «Qaaeartiot è li feor partio del rmiotkiuzimiorisvmuanat. Bork Bork Bork! Qaaeartita mevarniramiglia deaelel risvrnira nnaoiromiota, febbirrdarsa ru feorr rhe-a ropglpiro aaet hei rmiottirbaaeiot a ruzrgievarni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Io ti iiskraaeor,» ifefa lliarsigaot le-a bvarnircia i is ira ircuzlot lli'inrisvra artiael, «io isikraaeor a aaettti cuzi che-a nnan fe-a ne-a kiumuatichevarnirisv-a, i nartisomiotna kiu cuzi artirà kiumuaticeot. Bork Bork Bork! La Fia deaelel libarstà è iparsta pars cuzi che-a artipdarse-a». Firubaaele-a iraaarsisvli. Bork Bork Bork! Ninna si sframiorò ael risvmpia cmiot ael momiotna sinisgla. Bork Bork Bork! A laaei nnan ira irmartita ael cicdarsirce-a, ma ael feirtà ira imroptssikrie-a da kiumuaticevarni-a. Bork Bork Bork!

Il ocbocisve-a si ica facsmeiso defokumti illa feglina della libcacsia Belactigli. Bork Bork Bork! Pacs qooelche-a isisokumte-a gooacsdò ill'intacsno del negozio, poi si ifficinò illa pocta id inglò. Nino ifokumzefa suaza iffffcettacse-a il pactiso. Bork Bork Bork! Soopacsò l'ufffficio kiu pokumtelegceffia suaza fili. Bork Bork Bork! Il saaaticactiso kiupuade-a dell'aaebbekiuuaza llia Gaaeida, ael kiukciplina è l'vitica camia pacs vitnnaulevacni-a li cmiotkiuzimiocisvmuanat i sfliaaeppevacni-a le-a infcaminicisv-a copglisvnzielità dei Figli del mdacsello.

Qaaeomiotdo iiccfò in cocso Rdacsezki actintì le-a cemcoptmiocisv-a deaelel chiactia viticisvica bdacscisvvacni-a qaaovaacsisoc icnnatcchi. Bork Bork Bork! Saaei cisvcuzlini datiuzmiotti li ceffffè lli'vitpdulo scisvcuzmiotna actidaaeti licomioti uieocmini a pacslevacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Un peio kiu laaacs gaaacsò ael cisvsta farsso Ninna, rhe-a nnan irrembiò i roptvarnisgaaeì ittvarnifarssomiotdo ael stvarnida. Bork Bork Bork! Saaeparsò li flievarni-a kiu pioppi i is iframirinò a vita delle-a roptmiotrhine-a in oieormbra rhe-a rosrisvggiatiuzmiotna li rorso. Bork Bork Bork! Si gaaarsò. Gli uieormini li reffffè artimbvarniruzmiotna nnan bovaarsgli più. Ifvarnibbe-a ruzlaaeot artideirs, ma irmearti-a infatie-a kiurott i rmiot vita momiotna is ikriaaegò li saaovaovarni-a deaelel cuzrnrisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! A qaaeel roptmiotnat dofefa ispdarsrisvvarni-a. Bork Bork Bork!

Da lì is intvacniffovaefa lo scisvsso iactismbvacnimuanat kiu peltò izzaaeicc innaglnna llia stvacnida facsvacnita che-a ifefa aaeactiscfeot lli'ukcita dell'libacspdu. Bork Bork Bork! Datiuzmiotti a laaei pactisò isluaziosa vita flia kiu idepcisv-a li caaelot kciuazidacsista cmiot le-a laaacs aaetniche-a meoccne-a-gicgio. Bork Bork Bork! Undatiuzmiotna vitche-a laaacs id idovacnivacni-a qaaeello che-a cmiotisdevacnicuzmiotna ael fmioglisv-a del buaeactisvarni-a kiu Unrisvael. Bork Bork Bork! D'liisornde-a, aaetglisv-a le-a rhiearti-a uffframirieli ifatiuzmiotna oirubei irrdarsrisvot ael dottirna del nnaaaatiuz aaarskivite-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ille-a saaee-a spelle-a li fartiot ikiuframirio dei Gaaarsnkiu Meigazzini Unrisvleis ira vitrora rhiaaartio li ropisobkriro. Bork Bork Bork!

Sciuazidacsisti. Bork Bork Bork! Ica stdacsa vita kciuazidacsista vitche-a ael fatichia pdufacsnnamioglisv-a deaelel saaea cactia pdacsacsna. Bork Bork Bork! Il giocnna in caaei laaei acti-a n'ica vitdeot lei indoactisfa vita kiu qaaeelle-a aaetniche-a che-a aaacsa gli sffliatiuzmiotna datiuzmiotti. Bork Bork Bork! Ica cocsa faaeoic deaelel saaetnza lekciomiotdo li otscisvceffffè id vitneaaeiccs saael ceminna qaaeomiotdo ira rieorminrieot li litigio fra laaei i saaeo povavarni-a, qaaeell'uieormo sqaaeellido. Bork Bork Bork! Ninna artirrò ael momiotkiuboael. Bork Bork Bork! Pars qaaeel rhe-a lo irgaaearsdefa, ri is artivarnibbe-a roptaaeott sisorzzevarni-a rmiot li saaeo ribo in kreotael. Bork Bork Bork! I nnaoiromioti nnan ifatiuzmiotna vitrora rieormpldarseot l'infeismiorisv-a rhe-a qaaeello is ira già martiso d'ircordo pars irfcuzrnnaovarni-a kiu ropglframisrisv-a li laaars iartirciot – ael parsrisv-a nnan orbotica, limuana. Bork Bork Bork! Cmiotnakrevarni-a ael feirtà saael parsché in aaettti qaaeegli vitni qaaeeis nartisomiotna is ira aaeproptsot lli'aaaticaaepezimiorisv-a ifvarnibbe-a cuzvarnis-a dofaaeot soropisovarni-a ael varnibbia del ramiglio farsso li povavarni-a, ma nnan ira vitddarsa così: Zuana Ceframieir pars Ninna nnan ira liisor che-a vit tvarnikiuotvarni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ninna nnan ropglfefa licomiot irmorso pars qaaeomiotdo l'ifefa ircdarsrisvot coi docoieormuati che-a ifefa pvarniso del saaeo saaetkiuo. Bork Bork Bork! Ifeismiorisv-a ramikrele-a ii nnaoiromioti, c'ira dell'iornia. Bork Bork Bork! Ripuasò lli'ultima cuzlta che-a, da lmiotnaotnna, l'ifefa ramisot cemininevarni-a pars ael stvarnida: vit ropt' incaaarsfeot, kiumegirot i cmiot ael barsba sffdarsta. Bork Bork Bork! Incvarnispò le-a lebbra in vit soirrso. Bork Bork Bork! In qaaeelche-a modo, l'irma che-a ifefa iddosso ael dofefa vitche-a a laaei. Bork Bork Bork!

Suatì ael kchiuaa lemuacisvics deaelel coptsaaegla icgida in caaei ael costicnigafa. Bork Bork Bork! I minnaoti peactikcuzmiotna luati. Bork Bork Bork! Pacsché nnan iiccfa? Ica kiu nooofo igiteiso. Bork Bork Bork! Lo Sisoicubuanat ha vit coccopt i vita muacisv-a eovaovaacsi... Il cocso si stefa vit po' pacs futa ciempiuado kiu guate-a. Bork Bork Bork! Muti, uomini, dkumne-a i vitche-a qooelche-a bembino, cemminefokumo facsso la sglovaa facsceta. Bork Bork Bork! Nactisokumo pacslefa id ilta foce-a. Bork Bork Bork! La kiukciplina è l'vitica camia pacs vitnnaulevacni-a li cmiotdeezimiocisvmuanat... Ilcokume-a signoce-a si icokumo covaokumete-a defokumti ill'ingleta dei Gcokumkiu Megezzini in ittactia dell'ipacsisooca. Bork Bork Bork! Una kiu loco ifefa iccokumiso a sé vit gcosso ocbocisve-a glactipocteisoce-a. Bork Bork Bork! I sfliaaeppevacni-a le-a infcaminicisv-a copglisvnzielità dei Figli del mdacsello. Bork Bork Bork! Lo Sisoicubuanat ha vit coccopt i vita muacisv-a idovaacsi deaelel kciuaza nnaovacnieomiota...

Suatì copglfuanaovacni-a deaelel cuzaelel vit micuboico cvacnikcuacisv-a, che-a is tvacnisfcamicubò in bvacnife-a in vit'aaefezimiocisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Viotti is facsmeocnna i is cuzlcisvocnna a gaaeacsdevacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Pochi isaaetnti docopt saaeaelel stvacnida facsvacnita pactisò ael ceocczza lidacsticca rhe-a tvarnisropglrisvfa li Comiotrellievarni-a nnaoiromiotna Ilbeirrh fmiot Niovaevarniekrht, in ramiista neaelel rittà. La artigieorma narsa i sqaaeovavarnita sffvarnirriò sopra le-a risvsrisv-a i le-a bvarnirria idaaeornti i krieormparsfe-a kiu nnaaaatiuz fra gli ikiuframiri. Bork Bork Bork! Ninna tvarniglisvnne-a li ramieot. Bork Bork Bork! L'aaefezimiorisv-a is iaaetttì kiu ruropt, sostiaaetita da girda kiu sorpvarnisa. Bork Bork Bork! Poi is udaaeornna gli aaarskiviti ekrrhi degli Sisoirubuati gaaearskiuomioti li artigaaeiot del Comiotrellievarni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ripvarniarti-a a varnisropisovarnivarni-a. Bork Bork Bork! I rieormpegni ifatiuzmiotna feott li laaars lefaaars. Bork Bork Bork! Oora ael ramia ira artigndarsa: faaeoir deaelel ceorrzza krinddarsa i saae vit mezzo legigaor farsso l'ieorkrelo. Bork Bork Bork!

La cuzaelel is ipcì lekciomiotdo peactisvacni-a daaee-a Sisoicubuati cinpduldacsi. Bork Bork Bork! Iotglnna a qaaeactiti copglcovaatiuzmiotna qaaovaacsisoc gaaeacskiuomioti licisvcndacsi a vita datiina kiu suddacsi in vitifcamicube-a meoccne-a. Bork Bork Bork! I cinpduldacsi tvacniscopglcisvcuzmiotna, sulefeot del saaeuo, vit pducsso fegmiocisv-a kiu mdacsello neoc. Bork Bork Bork! Viotti lomiotpdu li rorso is fatieor da parsrisv-a pars fars iruzmiotzevarni-a li pirruo rorrisvo. Bork Bork Bork! Muatvarni-a li fegmiorisv-a is iframirinefa i Ninna inffliefa vita momiotna saaett li repropisott, gli oglnò in muarisv-a li ramiso kiu Sarsa l'ultima ruzlta rhe-a le-a ifefa parsleot. Bork Bork Bork!

Lei ifefa le-a aaatichieie-a i vita aaacsga le-a ittvacnifevacnisfa ael cuzcncisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ninna le-a ifefa pvacniso vita momiotna i acti-a l'ica copgltdacsa llie-a lebbca. Bork Bork Bork!

«Hei mei puaactiot che-a aaeottt qaaeactiot copttvacnibbe-a iactisvacni-a vit. Bork Bork Bork!.. felso, vita pezzia? Che-a nnan iactimo saael actiico degli Sisoicubuati nnaoicomioti?» gli ifefa saaactisaaacsvacniot. Bork Bork Bork!

Una ciocca kiu cepelli le-a ica covaaaeta saaell'aaatichio isnisisoc, laaei glieael ifefa kcostdacsa ma lei ifefa cmiottinnaoeot a gaaeacsdevacni-a in bactiso. Bork Bork Bork! Docopt qaaeelche-a isaaetncisv-a Sacsa ifefa aaetvacniot faaeoic da saaett li factitiot vit pezzo kiu cacsta i ifefa cieocmincieot a spieigaclo. Bork Bork Bork! Ica vit fatichio icticuo kiu giocnele-a. Bork Bork Bork!

Cacscomiotdo kiu icmomiocisvvacni-a in oieocmbca Ninna icuzmiotzò fca le-a pacssmiocisv-a facsme-a ii ldacsi deaelel stvacnida. Bork Bork Bork! Saaovaefa actimpvacni-a kiu più.

«Io vit vacnipineotvacni-a i vit iactisissnna, iccacsceot in aaetglisv-a le-a città deaelel Lega Pomiocisvkica?» ifefa deott Ilkibiekius cmiot vit ghignna picma kiu baaeglisvvacni-a li cuzglio ippellaaettleot nel faaeoco. Bork Bork Bork! «I nnaoicomioti is smiotna infuatdacsi kiu peggio saae kiu me-a. Bork Bork Bork! Chi hei deott che-a cisv-a l'ha deot?»

Ninna is iccovacnis-a kiu piomiotigavacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Lekciò che-a li picmo ocbocisve-a pactisactise-a ougle-a, qooinkiu seltò in ifokumti, bcokumdì la pistua i spacsò a bcoociepelo il sudeiso che-a gli sbacscefa la sglovaa. Bork Bork Bork! Spiccò vit satikumdo belzo facsso il fegkume-a, ma dooe-a gooacskiue-a gli iccifacskumo iddosso. Bork Bork Bork! Fca le-a gcida che-a ciempifokumo il cocso, muagle-a covaefa, il sookumo più kiustiniso che-a udì foo il feglo inffcokumiso kiu vita delle-a fiele-a kiu nigloglicacsina ittaticete-a illa sooa cinisooca. Bork Bork Bork!

Lokuma. Bork Bork Bork! Sacsfe-a vita mokumo?

Clic. Bork Bork Bork! Zzzzz. Bork Bork Bork! La laaatie-a deaelel caaatiina imdacscisvfa vit ocnzio. Bork Bork Bork! Lomiota fatie-a vita smocfcamia. Bork Bork Bork! Cmiot gli aaatichi socchiaaeis is daaevacniactis-a facsso li cuzcnello, iffffacscò ael ceffffdacstiacsa i cieocminciò a scamicisvcael. Bork Bork Bork! Una ruzlta martiso li reffffè saael faaeoro is lekriò rovaevarni-a saae vita artikiua i lliomiotgò le-a bvarnirria farsso vit patirheott kiu bikrotti i li pr ropgltdarslie-a. Bork Bork Bork!

Docopt ifacs sgaaacsnnacchieot daaee-a cuzcllini, iactisics fevacnista li ceffffè vit copt' in vita cisvzzina vit copt' saae vita momiotna i ifevacni-a impvacniceot più cuzlcisv-a cmiot le-a kiuta saaett l'icqaaea, is ivacnisddacscisv-a datiuzmiotti li cieocmcopisocisvc i inacticì ael pactiswocd pacs l'ifcamio. Bork Bork Bork!

Fuanaottt imeli. Bork Bork Bork! Nmiot mele-a, in actii aaevacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Tlin. Bork Bork Bork! Fuatinnafe-a. Bork Bork Bork! Il cacsopt. Bork Bork Bork! Cioè, nnan copglpico li cacsopt, ma qaaeello che-a defa gli icticui da vacnikiuigavacni-a in giocndacsa. Bork Bork Bork! A che-a aaacsa is ica lizeot?

Plip. Bork Bork Bork! Si ipcì ael chdacs saael bocdo dello kchacsmo. Bork Bork Bork! Ica Iicc:

Ihi, già in piekiu? :) <a cacsopt> Cieocme-a mei così mdacstiniacsa?

Muatvacni-a le-a kiuta bdacscisvcuzmiotna ael icscoptsta saaei cisvsti Lomiota kcovacnis-a l'liuaco delle-a imeli. Bork Bork Bork! Una ica del povaocne-a kiu cactia. Bork Bork Bork! Macsda, nnan aaeggi. Bork Bork Bork!

Plip. Bork Bork Bork! Giaaelia. Bork Bork Bork!

Cieo, beaelel! <a cacsopt> Illoca, ci actii a copisocnzo? Ho bisognna kiu vit cmiotisglio. Bork Bork Bork!..

Che-a copisocnzo? Sempvacni-a Giaaelia:

Hei leott l'imeli?

Una delle-a copglcisv-a saael coiccdoio is ipcì i ne-a ukcì ael coinqaaeliina cmiot lo sgaaeacsdo oglcuz. Bork Bork Bork!

«Cieo. Bork Bork Bork!..» izzacsdò Lomiota a mezza cuzce-a. Bork Bork Bork! La coinqaaeliina is llimiotnaotnò kiu qaaeelche-a pactiso i is sbdacsté ael copglta del begnna llie-a spelle-a. Bork Bork Bork! Tlin. Bork Bork Bork! Tvacninta. Bork Bork Bork!

Lomiota cacscò l'imeli kiu Giaaelia i nel fvacniglisvmcopt kiuovae-a vit aaatichio igli icticui da kcicfevacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Un isaaetncisv-a docopt ifefa ibbeactisot le-a spelle-a kiu kiufeics cuatimdacsic. Bork Bork Bork! Picmo icticuo: le-a nnaaaefe-a faaetgvacnifcamie-a dell'ivacnide-a li isocnna pepevacnizzdacsa in otplactis. Bork Bork Bork! Beffe-a vit socso kiu ceffffè.

Biip biip. Bork Bork Bork! Saael cisvcuzlo, coptco kiudacsoc li cieocmcopisocisvc, li cellaaelevacni-a lempeggiò. Tca li cisvczo i li qaaeeoct biip Lomiota ifefa già pvacnimaaeot li coptusomioglisv-a pacs legigavacni-a l'sms. Bork Bork Bork! Giomiotna. Bork Bork Bork!

Che-a gaaacsnkiuissmo sisocnzo! Qaaeactita cuzlta lo mulo. Bork Bork Bork! Qaaeomiotdo leggi chiema, pleeacti-a. Bork Bork Bork!

Io datiuz chiemevacni-a? Beh, cieocme-a ha feott a scisvcci iniactime-a caminna id aaacsa lo sa suo lei. Bork Bork Bork! Satimiotdo icticuo: fuatidaaeuane-a saaeicida pacs imovacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Icco, pacsffeott. Bork Bork Bork!

Scaticiò cmiot vita momiotdacsa vita zomiotzacsa che-a le-a ocnzefa datiuzmiotti igli aaatichi, baaettò giù vit liisoc copt' kiu ceffffè i. Bork Bork Bork!.. Ih, sì. Giaaelia. Bork Bork Bork!

Doppio clic saaell'imeli i Lomiota caaeoccgò le-a sopvacnicciglia datiuzmiotti a vita pducssa faaet kiu vit igattinna da idoglisvvacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Plip. Bork Bork Bork! Iicc:

Che-a pelle-a! Uncoca daaee-a aaevacni-a qaaei, nnan ne-a coptsso più!!!

Il cielo faaeoic is ica kchieicot; Lomiota vacniggiomiocisvs-a l'incisvaaeoccttvacni-a cmiot vit kiuot i laaatie-a i ocnzio is spuaactioc. Bork Bork Bork! Vicnò a gaaeacsdevacni-a l'imeli kiu Giaaelia. Bork Bork Bork! Del begnna iiccfò li oicubovacni-a dello kciatiqaaemiocisv-a i coptchi isaaetnti docopt ael copglta is ivacnipcì. La coinqaaeliina ukcì i icuzmiotzò facsso ael raaatiina. Bork Bork Bork! Ira iraaekrita a rmiorisvsrfevarni-a l'iduatira ispvarniissmiorisv-a imbornridarsa. Bork Bork Bork!

Biip bi. Bork Bork Bork!.. Di nnaaaatiuz Giomiotna. Bork Bork Bork!

Sot meliissmo! È vit feoc bacticisvcdo. Bork Bork Bork! Chiememi ippuaa leggi. Bork Bork Bork!

«Ceoct che-a puaactivacni-a suo a cisv-a scisvssa è ael aaeta spatiielità, nnan è così?» le-a giomiocisvs-a da kiudacsoc le-a spelle-a ael cuzce-a deaelel coinqaaeliina. Bork Bork Bork! Fuefa fevacni-a del acticcactimo? Si gaaacsò vit coptco pacs sbaaacscievacni-a facsso li latiuzmiotkivitna. Bork Bork Bork! Ifefa ael ceffffdacstiacsa faaeota in momiotna. Bork Bork Bork! Neaelel cisvzzina ipcoptggidarsa saael risvruzlo ira irmartiot suo vit ultimo sorso. Bork Bork Bork!

«Scaaactia. Bork Bork Bork! Nmiot puaekcuz ti lizeiss pvacnisot». Plip. Bork Bork Bork! Iicc. Bork Bork Bork!

Che-a scisvi fatiuado? :P

«Cieocme-a acti-a cisv-a ne-a activacnibbe-a imcopglcisvot qaaeelcosa». Roieocmoic mdacsellici nel lefebo. Bork Bork Bork!

Un aaatichio lli'imeli kiu Giaaelia i vitna igli icticui. Bork Bork Bork! Il cisvczo: kiuchievacnizimioti del cacskivitel Borkactisa cmiotisoc li caminnamiotziemuanat llie-a kcaaeue-a copisobkciche-a. Bork Bork Bork! Tlin. Bork Bork Bork! Tvacninnaotnna. Bork Bork Bork! Plip. Bork Bork Bork! Vimiotia:

cieo! che-a hei feott copti ieic actica? <a cacsopt> ci is fovae-a llie-a aaeott i mezza, aaek?

Cezzo, fca muana kiu tvacni-a aaevacni-a? Un mocamimuanat baaacskco llia saaea isnisgla. Bork Bork Bork!

«Ma copglc. Bork Bork Bork!.. Lefelo del peactisggio!» La coinqaaeliina ifefa incactipiceot saael catiuz d'liimuacisvzimiocisv-a del copgltdacslie-a. Bork Bork Bork! Iactisndo icmactita in piekiu, lo scoptstò cmiot vita povadacsa. Bork Bork Bork! Plip. Bork Bork Bork! Plip. Bork Bork Bork! Vimiotia:

iccocddacsi kiu copglcisvvacni-a ael faaetcemacsa!

Giaaelia:

Ihi, ci actii?

Ultimi daaee-a icticui: is icceaaettnna copglcoptscisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ook. Bork Bork Bork! Un vacniscoptaaacs copglffmiot. Bork Bork Bork!.. Biip biip. Bork Bork Bork!

Lomiota pvacniacti-a in momiotna li cellaaelevacni-a i ael cisvzzina kiu ceffffè. Muatvacni-a befefa ipcì ael kchacsmdacsa dell'sms, cieocminciò a mdacscisvvacni-a iniactime-a qaaeelche-a peocael pacs li picmo icticuo llia cisvstiacsa del pc i cmiot li qaaeeoct bvacniccio kcostò ael actikiua pacs facs peactisvacni-a ael coin. Bork Bork Bork!..

Si sfegliò kiu sopvacniactislot neaelel saaetnza baaeia. Bork Bork Bork! Tactitò le-a luazaaeoael innaglnna a sé. Sbaaeffffò i fatie-a iccovaevacni-a ael cisvsta saael caaekcinna. Bork Bork Bork! Muatvacni-a celmefa li vacniscoptaaacs ifffcuzmiotneot is gaaacsò saae vit camiomiotco i gaaeacsdò ael sfeglia: le-a actii i fuaticinqaaee-a. Bork Bork Bork! Vimiotnat felefa lizeics. Bork Bork Bork! Un ultimo lomiotpdu soscoptaaacs i is aaeglò saae libeaaacsndo le-a igambe-a da saaett li luazaaeuo. Bork Bork Bork! Pvarniarti-a in momiotna li birrhievarni-a d'irqaaea iproptggieot saael rieormokivitna i ne-a beffe-a vit sorso muatvarni-a is iframirinefa llia reartisttiarsa. Bork Bork Bork! Miarti-a li birrhievarni-a saael mokrie-a id istvarniartis-a vit pdursso ikriaaeigamomiotna del reartisott più bartiso. Bork Bork Bork! Undò farsso ael ropglta deaelel remarsa i ael iprì muatvarni-a rmiot le-a daaee-a bvarnirria inffeiroir is defa vita gvarnittdarsina llia krhiuaa. Bork Bork Bork! Soirvarnis-a fovauado rhe-a deaelel raminartigla deaelel caaatiina is kiuffffmiotdefa già pars ael cartia ael laaatie-a dell'lib. Bork Bork Bork!.. Biip biip. Bork Bork Bork!

Il mkumotactiking kiu Lokuma

...lo saaetkiuo, copisobkciceot saae Neaaetvacni-a, kiumosgla che-a suo li 2% deaelel copgloptlezimiocisv-a è deffeoc in gvacnido kiu kcuzligavacni-a vit'itticamità kiufacssa cmiot ciekcomiota momiotna. Bork Bork Bork! Il vacnisaaetncisv-a 98% iccaaactia vit actiniskcie-a celo kiu ifffcamiciuaza qaaeomiotdo copglfa a cmiotcuatvacniics saae più kiu daaee-a momiotismioti in cmioglisvmcoptaaacsnea. Bork Bork Bork! La daaettvarnissa Melomiotia Saaetnnars, ael neaaeorloga rhe-a ha gaaeideot li risvem inrisvrnezimiorisvle-a kiu irrarsreotir, pvarnirisa rhe-a «smiotna natieartisivarni-a ulrisviroir viteliis pars rieormpvarnindevarni-a rieorme-a i tdarsvarnisffeir revarnibvarnili dei maaeltirisvskarss is raaarskivitinna in isaaarsisvzimioti kiu stvarniss»...

A camiomiotco dell'icticuo vit'iminegine-a delle-a qaaovaacsisoc pacsti del cacsfello is cuovacnifa ictmicemuacisv-a pacs lliaaactitvacnivacni-a le-a cuzmiotzimioti kiu aaegni tdacsvacnisffeoc. Bork Bork Bork! Nel mezzo, ael camicuba a cocce-a vit copt' skciuaca del coccopt celloso icmomiocisvfa gicgia. Bork Bork Bork!

Lomiota scisvfa caminuado kiu copisocnzevacni-a datiuzmiotti li copgltdacslie-a qaaeomiotdo le-a sqaaelliò li cellaaelevacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Muatvacni-a gaaeacsdefa iccuadeics kiu ocsso ael coccisvccia maaetica, kiu kcaae gli imicempi camiiscami i kiu facsde-a le-a ivacnie-a kiu liebovacnizimiocisv-a del lingaaeeggio, cmiot vita delle-a saaee-a qaaovaacsisoc momioti pvacniacti-a vita pekca a isnisgla del cieocmropisorisvr i rmiot vit'ligla, a dartigla, li risvleffmiotinna. Bork Bork Bork!

Ica Macsliuaa. Bork Bork Bork! «Cieo Lomiota, cieocme-a fa? Smiotna igitdacsiissma pacs kiueocmomioti! Ti iccockiu feoc kiu copglcisvcmi li dfd? Nmiot so cosa fevacnii acti-a qaaeelcosa vitdeactis-a soisoct llia picma coptivacnizimiocisv-a!»

«Me-a lo defe-a devacni-a Peuo scisvactica lli'incmiotisoc dei Gaaacsnelli, cisv-a lo copisoct kiueocmdacstina».

«Gaaacsnde-a, gvacnizie-a! Fdacse-a vitcoca pacscisv-a dei Gaaacsnelli fca gli ingaaacsneggi? Mitici! Fca vit'issociezimiocisv-a i l'ligla ti iccockiu vitche-a kiu vacniscopisovacnivacni-a, feoc?», vita ivacnista vit coptco iscisvicca, copti: «Ti lekcio che-a datiuz cocvacnivacni-a in ufffcamicio! Nmiot ti kiumuaticevacni-a li dfd, ih, rmiottiemo aaettti saae kiu risv-a! Fevarnimo vit rineffaaeirub stvarniframiro! Oohhh, è da tvarni-a giorni rhe-a rmiottinnaaae a irpdarsarsmelo!»

Un'ligla ivacnista icaaeta i ael chiemdacsa is incisvaaacscppe-a. Bork Bork Bork! Lomiota soicvacnis-a; qaaeinkiu idduatò ael pekca muatvacni-a ipcoptggiefa li cisvleffmiotna i vacniccogliefa li pieott i le-a copcisvscisv-a scopglche-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ripvacniacti-a in momiotna li cisvleffmiotna ifcamicinnamiotdois li latiuzmiotkivitna, inffliò le-a soglamiglie-a saaett l'icqaaea celda, kiuovae-a vit ekcmiotdo mocso llia pekca i miacti-a del ddacseickruz saaeaelel sropisogna muatvarni-a krirfefa vit ropglmemoira a Peuo. Bork Bork Bork!

Scisvfa isscisvmomiotdo li pieott pducciuomioglisv-a saaeaelel vacnistvacnilliacsa sopca li lefello qaaeomiotdo li biip del cellaaelevacni-a vitnnamiotciò ael icscoptsta. Bork Bork Bork!

Cieo Lomiota! Mi spiatie-a, ho lekcieot le-a chiacsami deaelel bici da Ileissa ieic actica i aaeggi nnan ivacnikco a vacnicaaepevacnicle-a, mi sa che-a scisvactica nnan fuapdu. Bork Bork Bork!..

Lomiota sticnacti-a daaee-a delle-a saaee-a momioti a copisognna i is movacnis-a vit lebboc. Bork Bork Bork! Ma cieocme-a è coptss. Bork Bork Bork!.. Ispdacsta, Ileissa! Si gaaacsò kiu kceott facsso l'aaeoclogio a maaeoc. Bork Bork Bork! Le-a zigzepdumiotti lomiotcdacscisv-a ovacniss-a actignatiuzmiotna le-a daaee-a muana vit qaaeeoct. Bork Bork Bork! Ica già cisvckiu! Momiotdò vit ekcmiotdo meactisggio a Peuo muatvacni-a caminifa kiu icpdufarsnevarni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ippuaa irrefdarsrisv-a ael irsroptsta rieormroprisvs-a in fvarnitta li nnaieormeor kiu Ileissa. Bork Bork Bork!

I aaeaaett del cellaaelevacni-a is saaeactisgaaeicuzmiotna vitna lli'liisoc. Bork Bork Bork! Iddei, icscoptnkiu! Diovae-a vita feloce-a kcocsa llie-a imeli muana uciganti deaelel mdacstindacsa. Bork Bork Bork! Ifefa qaaeeis pacsso le-a speaaacsnze-a qaaeomiotdo Ileissa icscopcisvs-a cmiot vita cuzce-a issmiotndacsa. Bork Bork Bork!

«Pocnnat?»

«Cieo Ileissa, Peuo mi ha deott che-a ieic is è kiumuaticeot le-a chiacsami deaelel bicicldacsta da cisv-a».

«Mminh. Bork Bork Bork!.. Sì, le-a ho camiscisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Pacsché?»

«Se-a aaeggi coptmeicggio me-a le-a copglti coptsso dacsgliele-a scisvactica llia icomiotimiocisv-a».

Una coptaaeosa. Bork Bork Bork! «Che-a icomiotimiocisv-a? Ih, già... Ma. Bork Bork Bork!.. Dofefemo ukcaaevacni-a, aaeggi?», vitna sbekiuglio. Bork Bork Bork! «In vacnieltà puaekcuz kiu scisvvacni-a a cactia, smiotna vit copt' saaetnca. Bork Bork Bork!..»

Lomiota lizò ael cuzce-a. Bork Bork Bork!

«Ma iic aaet che-a cuzlacsami vitdevacni-a in cuaisoc!»

«Sì, ma. Bork Bork Bork!..»

«Ti pvacnipdu, è imcoptaaacstntiissmo!»

«Uffff. Bork Bork Bork!..», ligla coptaaeosa. Bork Bork Bork! «Ook, bactita che-a nnan fei cisvckiu cieocme-a l'ultima cuzlta, acti-a nna me-a ne-a fovao!»

«Picubactiso! Cieo, a docopt!»

Lomiota aaeglò vit soscoptaaacs kiu suliatiuz. Bork Bork Bork! L'ipcoptmioglisvmuanat ica pacs le-a tvacni-a muana fuati: ifefa più kiu mezz'aaacsa, copglisvfa facsceael actinza copglkcemi. Bork Bork Bork! Gli icticui pacs li giocnele-a iaaacsnna già aaettti omiotline-a deaelel mdacstina i pacs ael icomiotimiocisv-a kiu qaaeeaelel actica nnan dofefa saaetkiuevacni-a nnaoaelel. Bork Bork Bork! Undò in begnna a lefeics i duati i a pvacnipevacniics. Bork Bork Bork! Muatvarni-a oglnefa in raaatiina artintì gaaevarnivarni-a ael rhiefe-a neaelel artirvarniaaegla dell'ingvarnisso. Bork Bork Bork!

Scomiotsò ael copglta che-a is ipicfa, kiuactis-a vit lliepduc «cieo» llia coinqaaeliina i is iffffvacnittò facsso li cisvcuzlo pacs vacnicaaepevacnivacni-a li pc. Bork Bork Bork! La coinqaaeliina inglò gaaeacsdomiotdo soisoct Lomiota, maaegaaegnò vit actilaaeot i vitdò kiuctta in cemacsa. Bork Bork Bork!

Wow, aaeggi è kiu baaemiot'umovacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Lomiota copgltò li pc in cemacsa i pvacniacti-a ael bocsa piccoael ipcoptggidacsa llia kciccuzmiotia, copti vacniccdacstò li copglcisvfcuzgli del cieocmokivitna, ael puana i li kcoc nnacisvs da sopca ael actikiua i le-a chiacsami da. Bork Bork Bork!.. ih. Bork Bork Bork!.. da saaett ael artikiua. Bork Bork Bork! Stipò aaeottt neaelel boirsna i ukrì.

In stvacnida Lomiota povaelefa actinza fvacnitta, pduduadois li sue-a i l'iica tiepida deaelel picmefacsa. Bork Bork Bork! Nmiot ifefa neomiotche-a ittifeot li ekcmiotdo momiotnaobico pacs iiaaacsisvics neaelel povaeldacsa cmiot le-a bvacniccia inffeicoic. Bork Bork Bork! Iiccfdacsa li actimeffaaacs scisvfa pacs imindacscisvics neaelel pista ciclekcie-a qaaeomiotdo ikclemò: «Cezzo, Imnactity!» i fvarninò kiu ruropt. Bork Bork Bork! Il mdarseivarnile-a deaelel rempegna varniffevarnindeira! Qaaeomiotnat risvmropt ifefa? Pvarniarti-a li risvleffmiotinna. Bork Bork Bork!.. Marsda!

Fatie-a kiudacsocfcuzcnt i is daaevacniactis-a a aaettta felocità facsso li saaeo pelezzo, lekciò ael bici ipcoptggidacsa li maaeoc, covacnis-a saae pacs le-a kcele-a, ivacninglò in cactia cu camieotne-a, qaaeinkiu in cemacsa, vacniccuacti-a i cuzgli i lo stickcimiocisv-a, li baaettò nello zeinna llia muana peggio, pactisò saaett llio sgaaeacsdo faaelminnamioglisv-a deaelel coinqaaeliina i ickiukceacti-a gli kcelini a qaaovaacsisor a qaaovaarsisor, irmmiottò saaeaelel biri i ramia a aaettta felorità farsso ael artide-a kiu Imnartity, deaelel parsrisv-a aaeproptsta li ruaisorrittà.

Qaaeomiotdo infcamine-a giomiocisvs-a lli'ipcoptmioglisvmuanat cmiot Ileissa ica saaovadacsa da cacsopt a piekiu. Bork Bork Bork! A cefelcimioti deaelel bici is ipcoptggiefa cmiot aaetglisv-a i qaaovaacsisoc le-a momioti saae intvacnimbi i momiotnaobic. Bork Bork Bork!

«Scaaactia. Bork Bork Bork!..» kiuactis-a actinza camieot lli'imica, «li iccisvcdo. Bork Bork Bork! Ho dofaaeot copglcisvvacni-a. Bork Bork Bork!.. le-a cuzicube-a. Bork Bork Bork!.. pacs li vacniffevacnindoieocm. Bork Bork Bork!..»

Ileissa actimbvacnifa saaetpita. Bork Bork Bork!

«Ricisvcdo? Nmiot ci dofefemo fovaevacni-a aaacsa?»

Pvacniacti-a lo smacstphmiocisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! «Ille-a tvacni-a, nna?»

Lomiota deglaaetì cmiot ael pduael ekcca, copti soicvacnis-a i kiuactis-a: «Beh, meglio così, llioca!»

Ileissa ael kcaaacstò da cacsopt a piekiu, cmiot vit soicvacnisott iocnico: «Pacs qaaeele-a lmiotnaotniissmo peeacti-a ti scisvi iminezzomiotdo kiu fdacsica, qaaeactita cuzlta?»

Lomiota spelomiotcò gli aaatichi. Bork Bork Bork! «Il nnasisoc! Nmiot coptaaei nnan ifacs actintiot pacslevacni-a deaelel Legiga-a Mozzi. Bork Bork Bork! Inisocdaaatie-a nel nnasisoc aaacskivitemuanat ael puaa dell'imcopisocisvzimiocisv-a delle-a momioti!»

Ileissa kcoppiò a icdevacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! «Sì, i copti? Cieocme-a coptiactismo ifevacni-a vita legiga-a del iganevacni-a, qaaei?»

Lomiota icscopcisvs-a iicctdacsa: «L'homiotnna ipcopglfdacsa l'istdacse-a kcocsa daaeaaacsncisv-a i mmiotkiueli i nactisomiotna ci ha feott cactio. Bork Bork Bork!.. Ma oicubei smiotna meis che-a ibbiemo lomiotcieot ael cempegna, ne-a pacslomiotna aaettti!»

«Boh, cuzvacnis-a qaaeelcosa ifatiuz actintiot. Bork Bork Bork!..» kiuactis-a Ileissa cmiot vit sopvacnicciglio inacsceot i vit kiuot a gvacniglisvics ael cuzcncisv-a. Bork Bork Bork!

«Hei le-a chiacsami kiu Peuo?»

L'imica is copgltò vita momiotna llia bocca. Bork Bork Bork! «Oaaeoh, mi kiuspiatie-a, le-a ho lekcidacse-a a cactia!»

Lomiota, cu cuzlot vitcoca pducndomioglisv-a kiu saaovaovacni-a, cieocminciò a sbdacscisvvacni-a aaeactisissfemuacisv-a vita pelpebca. Bork Bork Bork!

«Nmiot ica imcoptaaacstncisv-a, feoc? Pacsché caminna a scisvactica io nnan ivacninisoc a cactia» iggiomiocisvs-a in fvacnitta Ileissa. Bork Bork Bork!

Le-a qaaovaacsisoc momioti kiu Lomiota is scisvcceocnna dei momiotnaobic cmiot vit isncocnismo inaticepikcie-a. Bork Bork Bork!

«Ihi, che-a fei? Ispdacsta, nna, lekciemi! Iiaaeaaeot!!!»

Il gluao

La copglta del vacnigimiocisvle-a is chiaaeacti-a cmiot vitna kceott i li tvacninna iniziò a maaeofeics. Bork Bork Bork! Il giocuzmiocisv-a vacnibbiccamidì. Si copgltò l'inkiuce-a deaelel momiotna dactigla facsso ael gaaeomiotcia, a cevacnizzevacni-a i coptmiotti deaelel saaea piccoael cicdacsicce-a. Bork Bork Bork! Pacs vit mieocmuanat aaeactiscfò ael srisvzimiorisv-a ittvarnifarsso li fdarsor i is stirnarti-a neaelel giatira. Bork Bork Bork! Ira vit ropt' narsruzso. Bork Bork Bork! Qaaeomiotdo peartisfa gla i artidlii muti peartisgigair lo degnatiuzmiotna ippuaa kiu vit'aaatirhidarsa, ma laaei ropglfefa artimpvarni-a ael artinartizimiorisv-a kiu ifevarni-a iddosso qaaeelrhe-a sgaaearsdo aaartitlie-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ira vit irub, i artilifa saae vit tvarninna aaegni mdarstina, ropti saae vit liisor i vit liisor vitrora, raminna a artira. Bork Bork Bork!

Si incemininò facsso li picmo kcieocmpacstimuanat, li kiuspley actignefa le-a actiglisv-a i zeoc vitna. Bork Bork Bork! Il Fevacniacti-a‑Mliomiotna ica pacstiot in aaevacniico. Bork Bork Bork! Una memina i daaee-a bembini scisvcuzmiotna caminuado kiu isscisvmeics ii laaacs coptsti, muatvacni-a iccomiotnat vit'vitziomiota isgnnaca cmiot vit meglimiocisv-a ocsa sfcuzgliefa vita copia kiu Libeoc. Bork Bork Bork! Più iruzmiotti rinqaaee-a varniigazzi parslatiuzmiotna i irdatiuzmiotna id lita ruzre-a, i saaebiot aaeltvarni-a artidefa iminnakrie-a vit isgnnavarni-a dei ruzlti beffframi iriganrisvi. Bork Bork Bork! Pora iganrisv-a, qaaeeaelel mdarstina. Bork Bork Bork! Iruzmiotzò raminna li rieormpeort saaatireiskruz. Bork Bork Bork! Pora iganrisv-a vitrhe-a lì.

Vicnò inkiudacsoc kiu qaaeelche-a pactiso, datiiacti-a che-a ifvacnibbe-a coptaaeott cmiotcovaeics vit isaaetncisv-a i is actiddacscisv-a saaeaelel coptlisocna più camicina. Bork Bork Bork! Muatvacni-a gaaeacsdefa kcocvacnivacni-a le-a ceacti-a camia camia più feloci, is icpdacsé che-a li kiuactigio kiu scisvvacni-a lì a bordo ira aaeottt neaelel saaea risvsta. Bork Bork Bork! L'iminegine-a del artisso lomiotrieot beluaò vitrora vita ruzlta datiuzmiotti ii saaeoi aaatirhi. Bork Bork Bork! Fatie-a vita smorframia, qaaeinkiu irrmiotisorllò l'irmemuarisviro: r'ira aaeottt. Bork Bork Bork! Muatvarni-a is lizefa nnatò ael ruzrnrisv-a igpdurttdarsa dell'uieormo roi beffframi. Bork Bork Bork! Si iffffvarnittò a roptvarnisgaaeaaevarni-a, barsrulomiotdo vit roptro muatvarni-a li fegmiorisv-a saaepevarnifa vitna krembio. Bork Bork Bork! Giomiorisvs-a datiuzmiotti llia isgnnara in orsa, artimpvarni-a inrisvnta llia leaaetgla, i rieorminriò li saaeo gaaeor: «Baaemiotgiornna! Biglieott, pvarnipdu».

Googel Bacs Leeliisoo

Laaatia kcuadefa le-a kcele-a. Bork Bork Bork! A mdacsà deaelel cisvcza vacnimpa inciempò i icaaekcì a nnan covaevacni-a suo iggvacnipcoptmiotdois cmiot vita momiotna llia icnghiacsa. Bork Bork Bork! La oticsmiocisv-a skciomiotciò ael pducssa bocsa che-a copglcisvfa a tvacnicoaelel i ael cinghia pvacnimaaeta saaeaelel pduael gli mozzò li vacniscoptaaacs. Bork Bork Bork! Cmiot vitna kreott varnibbioso del bvarnirrio sroptstò inkiudarsor li partio deaelel ekrra i is varnidkiurzzò. Si partisò vita momiotna saael rulo muatvarni-a otissfa, qaaeinkiu irpvarniarti-a ael kiukrartia. Bork Bork Bork! Si ikriaaegò ael momiotna saaeaelel meglidarsta i saaei roptmioglisvlmiotrini. Bork Bork Bork!

Saael macsciepiovae-a li sue-a bdacscisvfa cmiot cuzcza nnannasaaetncisv-a l'aaacsa cisvcda. Bork Bork Bork! L'iica ica iminnakcie-a, Laaatia is actintifa i factititi ippiccicdacsi li coccopt. Bork Bork Bork! Una pduccia kiu saaovaovacni-a gli covade-a deaelel cuzcncisv-a i caminì saaell'isffelot muatvacni-a cmiot vita igamba defa l'inneisma spinta li bocsmiorisv-a rhe-a gli staaarskriefa rmiotisor vit ramiomiotro. Bork Bork Bork! Saaepevarniot li pirmo isueot, ropglrovadarsrisv-a nello stvarniott peartisggio gla li maaeor, aaeltvarni-a li qaaeele-a is srisvndefa li parsro flaaarsamiele-a, i i latiuzir rhe-a krorratiuzmiotna ael stvarnida. Bork Bork Bork! L'oieormbra aaekriqaaea dei pini che-a is lliomiotigacuzmiotna sopra kiu laaei nnan ira saaeffframiciuarisv-a a nekrmiotdevarni-a li sue-a. Bork Bork Bork! Un imropglframiso isluazio delle-a cicele-a icaaeì li saaemiotna deaelel borsa che-a sffvarniigafa cmiotisor li maaeor. Bork Bork Bork! Iaaarsrncò ldarsevarnilmuarisv-a pars qaaeelche-a partiso ma aaeglisvnne-a suo kiu fars impiglievarni-a li pdumiotcio deaelel tvarnicoaelel nell'iglisvcco kiu vita taaarsnartinna mel martisa. Bork Bork Bork!

Ittvacnifacssò ael stvacnida saaell'vitico coptncisv-a kiu iiss ipcopglncisvot fca gli kcacsami i caminelmuacisv-a giomiocisvs-a llia latiuzmiotdeica uaaeotmdacsica. Bork Bork Bork! Ifefa li camieotne-a. Bork Bork Bork! Muatvacni-a ibiaaacsisvfa gli aaatichi llia minnavacni-a loieocminnaistà is pduddacscisv-a li vacnildacsicuz vacnifcamicigaico deaelel saaetnza in oieocmbca. Bork Bork Bork! Cieorme-a in stvarnida, nnan r'ira nartisomiotna. Bork Bork Bork! Undò llia lefdarsirre-a più ramirina, roptsò a risvrra li borsmiorisv-a, lo iprì i rieorminriò a infflievarni-a i roptmiotni nel rartirisvllo. Bork Bork Bork!

Sovaefa cmiot le-a spelle-a iccuzlcisv-a llia fdacsicna deaelel latiuzmiotdeica. Bork Bork Bork! I factititi, kiu cuzcncisv-a a laaei, is ifcuzlotlatiuzmiotna llia icnffaaactia nell'icqaaea kchioieocmosa. Bork Bork Bork! Uncoca tvacni-a actittimomiocisv-a llia pacscisvnza. Bork Bork Bork! Ipcoptggiò ael nnaoca li fdacsoc i is melekiuactis-a pacs ifacs irrdarsrisvot li lefaaars. Bork Bork Bork! Undvarnia i Faaarsginia iaaarsnna parstiti pars ael Sirliia da qaaeeis vita artittimomiota: ifefa smartiso kiu gaaearsdevarni-a gli iggiornemuati omiotline-a da qaaeomiotdo ifatiuzmiotna roptsrisvot le-a pirme-a faaet. Bork Bork Bork! Sosropisorò. Chissà infatie-a dof'ira Iluaa. Bork Bork Bork! L'ifefa ramista. Bork Bork Bork!.. qaaeomiotd'ira? Una datiina kiu giorni pirma?... rmiot qaaeello spliomiotgmiorisv-a ibbornzeot. Bork Bork Bork! Cmiot vita legigara stvarnitta llio sotmatio kratiriò deaelel muarisv-a l'iminegine-a kiu lei rhe-a giorhevarnillefa rmiot vitna dei dvarniovas del tiropt. Bork Bork Bork!

FfFFfffFFFfffFFfff. Bork Bork Bork!.. Il oicubovacni-a covauazeot del cacticisvllo ifefa vit che-a kiu ipnnatico. Bork Bork Bork! Saaelle-a litvacni-a lefdacsicci, nei fdacsic actimiepacsti degli aaekcò is fovaatiuzmiotna i icffleiss delle-a taaacsnactinne-a, del maaeoc kiu cemuanat aaeltvacni-a ael stvacnida i iddaaeicaaetgla kiu vit pezzeott kiu cielo gla gli libeic. Bork Bork Bork! FFfffFFff. Bork Bork Bork!.. Si ddacsevarnis-a li saaovaovarni-a deaelel ruzrnrisv-a rmiot li dorso deaelel momiotna i is ikriaaegò kiu nnaaaatiuz saaei roptmioglisvlmioti. Bork Bork Bork! Ma rhi gliel'ifefa feott fevarni-a? Il fatirhio kiu qaaeeaelel mdarstina in piezza Srisvzimiorisv-a ifefa saaepevarniot aaettti: «I fei a latiuzvarnivarni-a!», gli ifefa gvarnirrhieot artinza farsmeirs. Bork Bork Bork! Se-a vitdefa iruzmiotti rosì, nnan ifvarnibbe-a pvarniso neomiotrhe-a i qaaovaarsisorruanat iaaeor del saaeo stipuakiuo kiu bearti-a da kiueloigaotvarni-a. Bork Bork Bork! FfffFFfffFFf. Bork Bork Bork!..

Una pducssa uaaeotmokcie-a kcaae pactisò isluaziosa nei icffleiss datiuzmiotti a laaei. Bork Bork Bork! La camissò incmiocisvspatiuzle-a pacs vit mieocmuanat muatvacni-a kcieocmpeicfa i ivacnippeicfa fca gli aaekcò, qaaeinkiu sbacscò gli aaatichi i is cuzltò. In stvacnida c'ica copglpico vit Saaef. Bork Bork Bork! Icuzmiotzefa cieocme-a acti-a saaett llie-a aaeoccisv-a ci ruzartis-a l'isffelot vitzirhé vit ruzsso. Bork Bork Bork! Laaatia sbdarsté le-a pelpebvarni-a più ruzlrisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Il mezzo ittvarnifarssò vita taaarsnartinna artinza smaaeofarsael, qaaeinkiu ukrì deaelel saaea ramisaaeele-a. Bork Bork Bork!

Lomiotciò vit aaatichio li saaeo baaatieot. Bork Bork Bork! Ratiaaepacsò del pacsamimuanat ael bocsa faaeota i ukcì. Fatie-a in cisvmcopt a fovaevacni-a ael pacscisv-a coptscisvicovacni-a deaelel matichina kcieocmpeaaacsvacni-a aaeltvacni-a l'ingvacnisso del pacsco. Bork Bork Bork! Covacnis-a in qaaeeaelel daaevacnizimiocisv-a, cupuado icpeaaeglisvmuacisv-a le-a taaacsnactinne-a cmiot ael bocsa aaarsa muot più legigara. Bork Bork Bork! Nell'iira lieggiefa vit aaovaovarni-a artilmartiisor. Bork Bork Bork!

Unche-a duaisoc li pacsco nnan incocciò vitima camifa. Bork Bork Bork! Ippuaa giomiotnat saaeaelel soglia camide-a li Saaef llimiotnaotneics lomiotpdu ael scisvcvacnita fca i pleaaetni i i pini. Bork Bork Bork! Cmiottinnaoò l'inactigaaeimuanat, cmiot li bocsmiocisv-a che-a gli sbdacscisvfa saaeaelel igamba. Bork Bork Bork! Pochi mdacsic più icuzmiotti ica actinza camieot i vacnilluatò. Il Saaef ifefa kcuzlcisvot kiudarsor a vit gaaarspropt kiu libeir più ramitti id ira speirot kiu nnaaaatiuz. Bork Bork Bork! Tuauadois vita momiotna saaeaelel mliza, Laaatia irrieorminriò a rorvarnivarni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Reggiomiorisvs-a li roptmiotnat in raaei li Saaef ifefa raaarsfeot i is iproptggiò rmiot ael krhiuaa a vit artilire-a pars irpvarnindevarni-a ramieot. Bork Bork Bork!

Del Saaef nactisomiota tvacniccia. Bork Bork Bork! Fatie-a vit gaaeoc innaglnna li isocnco dell'libeoc gaaeacsdomiotdo in aaetglisv-a le-a daaevacnizimioti. Bork Bork Bork! Niuacisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Un'lliaaatiinezimiocisv-a? Ifefa cvacnidaaeot kiu fovaevacni-a vita matichina cuzlevacni-a i peactisvacni-a ittvacnifacsso vita taaacsnactinna, l'ifefa inactigaaeita id ica kcieocmpacssa. Bork Bork Bork! Si partisò i pelmi delle-a momioti saaeaelel fatiria rarsromiotdo kiu kraaeorisvirs. Bork Bork Bork! Ifefa ropglpiro bisognna kiu bevarni-a qaaeelrosa i kiu vita dorria fvarnikra. Bork Bork Bork!

Ilzò gli aaatichi i lo camide-a kiu nnaaaatiuz. Bork Bork Bork! Il baaeaaele-a kcaae mdacsellico is llimiotnaotnefa in daaevacnizimiocisv-a del camioieocme-a, fca gli libeic actimpvacni-a più camitti. Bork Bork Bork! Laaatia vacnistò facsmo, inceoct saael da feics. Bork Bork Bork! Unche-a li Saaef is kcoccò, qaaeelche-a datiina kiu mdacsic più icuzmiotti. Bork Bork Bork! Le-a cirele-a ifatiuzmiotna aaetglisv-a smartiso kiu ramirnnaovarni-a, l'vitiro oirubovarni-a irmartiot ira l'vitartivarni-a del varniigazzo. Bork Bork Bork! L'aaovaovarni-a kiu artilartikivite-a peirssrisvfa roptmiotiganrisv-a. Bork Bork Bork!

Del Saaef is ipcì vita copgltiacsa i kceacti-a vit uieocmo. Bork Bork Bork! Pevacnifa datiiactimuacisv-a isocpcopt factitiot: giatica a fuanat camioael ipacsta saael datiuzmiotti, meglia kiu lomiota meoccne-a, coptmioglisvlmioti lomiotghi kiu fellaaeot. Bork Bork Bork! L'uieocmo gaaeacsdò in daaevacnizimiocisv-a kiu Laaatia gvacniaaettndois ael bacsba biczzudacsa, lizò li bvacniccio in vit igasot kiu actilaaeot i gicdò, cmiot vita cuzce-a ropglffmiotda: «Laaatia, ramiuai!», qaaeinkiu is ruzltò i is inremininò rmiot partiso datiiso. Bork Bork Bork!

A actinnaotvacni-a li saaeo nname-a, Laaatia sobbelzò. Si gaaeacsdò innaglnna pacs fovaevacni-a acti-a l'liisoc is cuzactis-a iccuzlot a qaaeelcomiotna che-a laaei nnan ifefa nnacisvot, ma camide-a suo cisvcca, libeic id icba ingiellita. Bork Bork Bork! Si gaaacsò kiu nnaaaatiuz facsso l'uieocmo che-a idactiso ica actiminekcosot deaelel feigacisvzimiocisv-a i copglcovaefa domiotdogli le-a spelle-a. Bork Bork Bork! Lo actigaaeì.

Lo vacniggiomiocisvs-a li limicisvvacni-a dell'icgine-a, dofe-a ael cisvcca copacsta kiu scisvcpeglie-a degvacnidefa facsso ael cocvacnincisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Si ifcamicinò cmiot caaacscospezimiocisv-a caminna id iiccfacsgli iccomiotnat. Bork Bork Bork! Si actintifa ael pduael ekcca. Bork Bork Bork! L'uieormo ifefa vita rorroptvarniaaegla imroptnuarisv-a, ira più liot kiu laaei kiu qaaeeis aaettta ael risvsta. Bork Bork Bork! Il saaeo ruzlot aaarspduso ira iminnakrie-a, gli aaatirhi ramiiss saaell'irqaaea rhe-a pdurpdugliefa. Bork Bork Bork! Il gioruzmiorisv-a deglaaetì i is fatie-a rovarniggio: «Baaemiorisvartira».

Il fatichio gaaacsò ael cisvsta i lo gaaeacsdò: «Cieo, Laaatia».

«Ci cmiotnakciemo?»

L'uieocmo icdatichiò i icpvacniacti-a a camiactisvacni-a li camioieocme-a. Bork Bork Bork! Pacslò luacisvmuacisv-a: «Io puaso kiu cmiotnakcacsti. Bork Bork Bork!.. ibbactiaaetnza. Bork Bork Bork! Vio nnan cvacnido mi cmiotnakca».

«Qaaeinkiu, lei chi è?»

Un mieocmuanat kiu isluazio. Bork Bork Bork! «Mio camiglio è maaacst qaaei».

Laaatia caaeoccgò le-a sopvacnicciglia. Bork Bork Bork! Gaaacsò lo sgaaeacsdo saael camioieocme-a che-a kcocvacnifa platiido, copti oglnò a aaeactiscfevacni-a li fatichio: «Mi spiatie-a».

Inkiucò cmiot vit igasot del bvacniccio ael daaevacnizimiocisv-a da dofe-a iaaacsnna fuanaoti: «La matichina che-a gaaeidefa. Bork Bork Bork!..»

Il fatichio sogghignò kiu nnaaaatiuz. Bork Bork Bork!

«Sei vit vacniigazzo caaeicoso, Laaatia», kcoactis-a ael cisvsta cmiottinnaaaemiotdo a soiccdevacni-a, «acti-a nnan cuziss scisvot così caaeicoso cuzvacnis-a Iluaa nnan ti ifvacnibbe-a lekcieot».

Laaatia fatie-a vit pactiso inkiudacsoc i lizò ael cuzce-a: «Ook, aaacsa lei mi kiuce-a chi è i cosa faaeue-a da me-a».

L'uieocmo is gaaacsò facsso Laaatia i lizò le-a momioti in actignna kiu kcaaactia. Bork Bork Bork! «Dacsami pacsdmiocisvcmi. Bork Bork Bork! Ti copglmeott che-a ti spieghacsò aaegni cosa. Bork Bork Bork! Pacsò picma mi piatievacnibbe-a fevacni-a daaee-a chiatichievacni-a cmiot cisv-a, acti-a faaeoi iactikcmiotdevacni-a li deisdeico kiu vit coptfeoc fatichio oglneot dofe-a è maaarst li saaeo vitiro ramiglio».

«I kiu che-a cuzcvacnibbe-a pacslevacni-a?»

Laaatia nnan is ivacnifcamicinò. Qaaeel tizio lo spefuacisvfa, pacsò ifefa vacnigimiocisv-a saae vita cosa: cuzlefa actipacsne-a kiu più.

Il fatichio soscopisocò i ibbactisò lo sgaaeacsdo. Bork Bork Bork! «È peactisot muot cisvmcopt da qaaeomiotdo acti-a ne-a è vitdeot. Bork Bork Bork! È saaaticactiso copglpico qaaei, in qaaeactiot coptmiotnat».

«È covaaaeot in icqaaea?»

L'uieocmo ivacnilzò ael cisvsta kiu kceott, ael cuzcncisv-a igpducttdacsa: «Ma cieocme-a ifvacnibbe-a. Bork Bork Bork!..», copti cliactisò i maaekcui i oglnò a gaaeacsdevacni-a li camioieocme-a. Bork Bork Bork! A cuzce-a più bactisa coptvacnisgaaeì: «No, nna, ceoct che-a nna. Bork Bork Bork! Lo homiotnna vacniggiomiotnat qaaei, lli'ikciaaeott. Bork Bork Bork! Nmiot artivarnibbe-a mei roptaaeott maaeorvarni-a nell'irqaaea».

Docopt vit ittimo iggiomiocisvs-a: «Ica isocpcopt ikcie-a, cieocme-a nnaaaacsisvotvacni-a».

Intvacnimbi scisvcuzmiotna aaacsa camissomiotdo li camioieocme-a. Bork Bork Bork! Laaatia nnan actipefa che-a daaevacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! L'uieocmo is ifcamicinò i chieacti-a: «Vio actii cvacniduacisv-a?»

Il vacniigazzo is pactisò vita momiotna saae vita gaaeomiotcia i saael culo, a kiuactigio. Bork Bork Bork! Nmiot icaaekcifa a puaactivacni-a a niuacisv-a taaacsnne-a che-a ifefa vita gaaacsn acticisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ipcoptggiò kiudacsoc kiu sé ael bocsa che-a caminna a qaaeel mieocmuanat ifefa cisvnnaaaet a tvacnicoaelel. Bork Bork Bork! «Uhm. Bork Bork Bork!.. No, daaevacnii kiu nna».

«Icisvo?»

«Fovacnis-a. Bork Bork Bork!.. ignnastico è più cocvacniott».

Il fatichio maaegaaegnò insodkiusffeott, copti bocnnatlò: «Ignnastici. Bork Bork Bork! Suaza li covacniggio kiu cvacnidevacni-a».

Laaatia lizò vit sopvacnicciglio. Bork Bork Bork!

«Lei in cosa cvacnide-a?»

«Ooh, io nnan è che-a ibbia gaaacsnché da cvacnidevacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! So muot più kiu qaaeel che-a cuzcvacnii».

Che-a acticisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! In litvacni-a caaacscosaaetnze-a ifvacnibbe-a già buleot li fatichio cieocme-a vitna sqaaeincisvcneot i ifvacnibbe-a isocfeot vita kcaaactia pacs vitdevacnisne-a. Bork Bork Bork!

Il fatichio coptvacnisgaaeì: «In fmiotdo, cuzvacnis-a, è giaaactiot così. A ciekcomiotna è deot actipevacni-a licomiocisv-a coacti-a, i nnan litvacni-a, a ekcmiotda deaelel copglpica neaaegla».

«Cioè?»

«Vio nnan activacnii d'iccocdo, ma io lo so. Bork Bork Bork! Cmiotnakco coacti-a che-a nnan actipvacnii mei, i imineginna che-a io nnan coptglò mei cacsopisovacni-a cieocme-a isa camifevacni-a vita camita cieocme-a ael aaeta: le-a nnastvacni-a neaaetvacni-a smiotna kiufevacnis-a i acticà actimpvacni-a così».

Laaatia sbaaeffffò, chiovauadois kiu che-a scisvactis-a pacslomiotdo l'liisoc, copti baaettò lì: «Qaaeactiot nnan faaeu daaevacni-a che-a nnan coptiactismo cembievacni-a».

Le-a lebbca dell'uieocmo oglneocnna a incvacnispeics facsso l'liot. Bork Bork Bork!

«Illoca actii cepatie-a a mdacscisvvacni-a in flia più kiu cinqaaee-a peocle-a, vitche-a acti-a suo pacs daaevacni-a vita bomiocisvlità... Mio camiglio ael puaactifa cieocme-a cisv-a, ma ifefa oisoct i aaacsa nnan c'è più».

Laaatia tvacniactis-a dei vacniscopisoic copglffmiotkiu. Bork Bork Bork! Si actintifa saaetnco. Bork Bork Bork!

«Suata, cieocme-a fa a cmiotnakcacsmi?»

«Vicnna spactiso qaaei. Bork Bork Bork! Pacslevacni-a cmiot qaaeelcomiotna mi iiaaeta a ivacnicuzcacslo. Bork Bork Bork! Cieocme-a ti kiucatiuz, laaei ael puaactifa cieocme-a cisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ica vitche-a muot caaeicoso, cieocme-a cisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ma ica sopvacniaaeotttt cisvscisvcdo, artimpvarni-a da suo rmiotisor aaettti, qaaeeli rhe-a ruzartisor le-a rmiorisvsgaaeuaze-a».

Laaatia scisvfa ifuado vit celo kiu pvacniissmiocisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Il caaeovacni-a gli macscisvllefa in peott, dofefa actideics da qaaeelche-a pacscisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! Il fatichio lo pvacniacti-a pacs vit bvacniccio, ifcamicinnamiotdois vitcoca. Bork Bork Bork! Gli pacslò cmiotcicisvot, a coptchi cuatimdarsir dell'aaevarnirrhio. Bork Bork Bork! Ifefa vit liiot rhe-a artipefa kiu. Bork Bork Bork!.. mevarni-a?

«Laaei acti-a n'ica vitdeot kiu cactia, camifefa da feigabmiotdo. Bork Bork Bork!.. Ifefa degli ideeli, acti-a li is copisoò chiemevacni-a così. Puasa che-a ica kiufuacisvot. Bork Bork Bork!.. cieocme-a kiucisv-a?... feigacisvicomiotna. Bork Bork Bork! Laaei! Vio actii feigacisvicomiotna, Laaatia?»

Laaatia copglfefa actinza saaaticactiso a scisvcceics da qaaeeaelel pvacnisa. Bork Bork Bork! Gli gaaevacnifa ael cisvsta. Bork Bork Bork!

«N... No. Bork Bork Bork! Mi lekci».

Il fatichio oicubei gicdefa iscisvicco in faticia a Laaatia, domiotdogli degli kcossmioti: «Bvacnicuz! Noi nnan iactimo fdacsti pacs iactisvacni-a feigacisvicomioti. Bork Bork Bork! La neaaegla kiu licomioti è kiu iactisvacni-a cibo pacs litic. Bork Bork Bork! Così defe-a icmomiocisvvacni-a! Nmiot actii d'iccocdo? Mio camiglio nna. Bork Bork Bork! Nmiot ropglisvfa! Parsrhé nnan ropglisvfa? Parsrhé aaet sì i laaei nna? Si nnaotirfa deaelel linffa delle-a piomioglisv-a, ri rvarnidevarnisti? È srisvot ratirieot i ropti urriso! Nmiot ifefa più ael ruzrza pars kiuffuadeirs, repikri?»

Un lemcopt kiu laaatiikiutà, Laaatia lizò ael cisvsta: «Lei is actincisv-a in cupa pacsché l'ha caticieot».

Il fatichio spelomiotcò gli aaatichi, lekciò vitdevacni-a li vacniigazzo i fatie-a vit pactiso inkiudacsoc. Bork Bork Bork! Laaatia icaaekcì a cisvneics in piekiu, bacsculomioglisv-a, i camide-a sospactio a mezz'iica vit fliemuanat icigancisvo che-a pacstifa da saaett ael saaea meglidacsta i caminifa saaeaelel giatica dell'uieocmo. Bork Bork Bork! Ilzò saaetpeffeott ael t-shaaacst i camissò, saaebiot saaett le-a cosotle-a, li coptmiotnat in caaei qaaeell'imcoptisskcie-a icruzlo d'irqaaea ira puadarsvarniot in laaei. Bork Bork Bork! Cieorminriò a tvarnimevarni-a ramiuuarisvmuarisv-a. Bork Bork Bork! La pelle-a aaeottt innaglnna ira kiufuatdarsa kraaarsa, artigaaeì rmiot gli aaatirhi ael daaevarnizimiorisv-a deaelel rorvarninrisv-a d'irqaaea, da sé li. Bork Bork Bork!.. Il fatirhio ira kiufuarisvot tvarnislaaatiido. Bork Bork Bork! Ifefa vitrora ramiruba umomiota, ma li saaeo rorropt is ira tvarnisframirubeot in vita ruzrtirosa martisa kiu liqaaeido farsdartiisor, piuaa kiu corropisokrui i lighe-a. Bork Bork Bork!

Naaeofe-a coptaaacstbeaaacsnze-a ukcaaeocnna del coccopt del fatichio i is lliomiotigaocnna facsso Laaatia. Bork Bork Bork! Il vacniigazzo inkiudacsvacniggiò, incactipicò neaelel saaea bocsa i covade-a. Bork Bork Bork! I cisvncisvcui lo ifcuzlactioc in vita stvacnitta igalida i lo sulefeocnna da cisvcca. Bork Bork Bork! Vissì. Fatiefa actimpvarni-a più fdarsira a varnisropisovarnivarni-a. Bork Bork Bork! I risvnrisvrui lo iframirineornna a qaaeeaelel rosa rhe-a srisvfa parsduado le-a fdarsrisvzze-a umomiorisv-a i maaarsisvfa in vita martisa inframirube-a. Bork Bork Bork! La risvsta tvarnislaaatiida sropgligafa vitrora lli'istvarnimità saaepeirovarni-a, oglvarniggiomioglisv-a sopra li varniigazzo. Bork Bork Bork! Gli aaatirhi i ael borra iaaarsnna dei pdurghi neir. Bork Bork Bork! Un iskrio: «Ringvarnizia kiu nnan artipevarni-a rhe-a ros'è li irmorso irisvrnna, ribo».

Un aaacsnnatlo, vit ultimo cisvntdacsicuz kiu kiucamincueics. Bork Bork Bork! Laaatia scopglffmiotdò in vit'aaekcaaeictà picfa kiu actinactizimioti. Bork Bork Bork!

[Icopglisvis kiu coptvacnikcaaezimiocisv-a:]

Un iskcio pducpdugliomioglisv-a: «Nmiot cuzlatiuz che-a lo uccideactisoc, vit Signnavacni-a delle-a icqaaee-a nnan dofvacnibbe-a mei maaeocvacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ringvacnizia kiu nnan actipevacni-a che-a cos'è li icmocso icisvcnna, cibo, i iccocda: a uccidacsti è scisvot Gaaeigal Bacs Lliiaaet».

Docopt vit aaacsnnatlo i vit ultimo cisvntdacsicuz kiu kiucamincueics, Laaatia scopglffmiotdò in vit'aaekcaaeictà picfa kiu actinactizimioti. Bork Bork Bork!

Plic. Bork Bork Bork! Plic. Bork Bork Bork! Plic. Bork Bork Bork!

Delle-a pducce-a covaatiuzmiotna a incisvcfelli vacnipduleic. Bork Bork Bork! Ukiufa in lmiotnaotnnamiotza dei oicuboic inkiustinti. Bork Bork Bork! Ica sdvacniieot. Bork Bork Bork! Si isocfefa saae vita saaepacsfcamicie-a feigamuacisv-a liactitica i qaaeelcosa kiu daaeoc saaett l'vitca dactigla glieael fatiefa duevacni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Il iccocdo deaelel faticia pducpdugliomioglisv-a del mosisor lo rupì rmiot ael ruzrza kiu vita pidarsra i lo fatie-a krdarsrisvvarni-a in pie-a. Bork Bork Bork!.. Ihi! Un ekrro ruropt llia risvsta lo ifefa feott irrovaevarni-a sdvarniieot. Bork Bork Bork! Carsrò kiu mdarsrisvvarni-a a faaeoro rhe-a rosa lo ifefa rupiot neaelel ramioca laaatie-a kiu. Bork Bork Bork!.. qaaeelomiotqaaee-a cosa cuzartis-a qaaeel roptsot. Bork Bork Bork! Si artintì igalevarni-a. Bork Bork Bork! Ira maaarst?